Finding aid to the Marian Sage Seewoster papers CA.MS.00020
Smith College Archives
Marian Sage Seewoster papers
1927-1986
1927-1928
Smith College Archives
Seewoster, Marian Sage, 1907-1999.
CA.MS.00020
0.208 linear feet (1 container)
Smith graduate. Contains correspondence from junior year abroad and postcards.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Marion Sage Seewoster Papers were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Biographical / Historical
Marian Sage Seewoster was born Marian Strong Sage on December 11, 1907 in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania. The daughter of Herbert Strong Sage and Katherine Corkery, Marian attended the Wilkes-Barre Institute before beginning her studies at Smith College. Marian graduated with the class of 1929 after spending her junior year abroad in Paris, France at the University of Paris. She did graduate work at Washington University in St. Louis, MO.
In St. Louis, Marian taught French at the Mary Institute, now the Mary Institute and St. Louis Country Day School, for 36 years, taught English to foreign students at the International Institute, and was active in community organizations that promoted French culture. These included the Alliance Francaise, Societe Francaise, and the American Association of the Teachers of French. She married Charles C. Seewoster and had a son, Charles Sage Seewoster in (1951?) Charles, Sr. died in 1972. Marian died on July 30, 1999 in St. Louis, MO at the age of 91.
Related Material
80. Class of 1929 Records
Scope and Contents
While attending her Junior Year in Paris she sent numerous letters home to her parents in Wilkes-Barre. This is a collection of those letters - kept and numbered by her parents as they were received - along with an incomplete set of transcriptions and miscellaneous correspondence received by Marian later in her life.
Foreign study--France--Paris.; Seewoster, Marian Sage, 1907-1999.; Smith College--Students.
- JYA Correspondence, Aug 19-Sep 19 1927 (Box 2019.1, Folder 1)
- JYA Correspondence, Sep 25-Oct 6 1927 (Box 2019.1, Folder 2)
- JYA Correspondence, Oct 9-27 1927 (Box 2019.1, Folder 3)
- JYA Correspondence, Nov 3-13 1927 (Box 2019.1, Folder 4)
- JYA Correspondence, Nov 16 1927-undated (Box 2019.1, Folder 5)
- JYA Correspondence, Dec 4-26 1927 (Box 2019.1, Folder 6)
- JYA Correspondence, Dec 30 1927-Jan 15 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 7)
- JYA Correspondence, Jan 20-Feb 10 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 8)
- JYA Correspondence, Feb 12-Mar 8 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 9)
- JYA Correspondence, Mar 12-Apr 6 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 10)
- JYA Correspondence, Apr 13-17 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence from Cornelia B. Sage Quinton, Mar 11 1927 (Box 2019.1, Folder 12)
- Postcards from various people, 1947-1986 (Box 2019.1, Folder 13-15)
- Transcripts of correspondence by Unknown Author, 1927; Aug 19-Sep 19 (Box 2019.1, Folder 16)
- Transcripts of correspondence, Nov 27 1927-Jan 15 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 17)
- Transcripts of correspondence, Jan 30-Mar 12 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 18)
- Transcripts of correspondence, Mar 25-May 7 1928 (Box 2019.1, Folder 19)